## Alice Richardson

Fort Collins, CO | 970-817-1904 | Alice.richardson.dev@gmail.com | GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn

#### INTRODUCTION

I moved from my home country of Thailand to the U.S. 5 years ago, and I am a permanent resident with legal working status. I have worked my way up, starting as a waitress, until I found my passion in coding. I am a full stack software developer with a bachelor's degree in design from Bangkok University. I am personable with a talent for developing solid relationships with co-workers and clients. My work ethic and dedication to exceeding expectations is what keeps me motivated to impress, and I continuously strive to improve my craft.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails, SQL, Mongo DB, Javascript, Node. Js, React. Js, Vue. Js, React native (expo), Bootstrap, Material-UI, Git / Github, AWS

#### **GENERALSKILLS / API INTEGRATION**

Microsoft office, Photoshop, Autocad, Sketchup, Customer service, Google API, Sendgrid API

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Ecofreak // MEVN | AWS EC2 - Github | Website URL

Web application to inspire environmentally safe practices, and learn how to lessen one's environmental footprint

- Created and styled frontend with Vue and MD bootstrap
- Built collaborative blog interface for users to share and contribute ideas to better help the world
- Created own API to allow users to save directly to database

# Parking Spot Finder // Ruby | Rails | React-native | Heroku | AsyncStorage - Github | Demo

Mobile application to help users find a parking spot near their current location or destination

- Created a secure login using JSON web Tokens and AsyncStorage
- Enabled seamless mobile iOS and Android UX via React Native and Expo
- Integrated Google Maps API and Google Places API to locate users by on longitude and latitude

## Thai Alphabet Flashcards // Ruby | Rails | Javascript - Github | Demo

Web application to help learn Thai language, with a mix-and-match game

- Made a mix-and-match memorization game with time limit and dynamic scoring using Javascript
- Designed clean and simple UI/UX for a focused learning experience
- Included audible readouts of letters to aid the visually impared

# Coffee Shop // Ruby | Rails | Javascript | HTML | CSS - Github | Demo

Web application to help coffee shop owners keep track of their stock

- Built Full CRUD backend with Ruby on Rails
- Used Javascript, HTML and CSS to style
- Manipulated and set the HTML content of an element using DOM

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

- Speaker at Women Who Code Boulder/Denver Monthly Meetup

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Waitress | Café de Bangkok

April 2017- Present | Fort Collins, CO

- Provided outstanding customer service by engaging diners and meeting their needs
- Responded professionally to customer questions and requests

### **Expanded Duty Dental Assistant | Davis Family Dental**

April 2018- Nov 2019 | Loveland, CO

- Ensured patient satisfaction through education, expectation setting, and treatment explanation
- · Performed office, and lab duties, and often worked chair-side to directly assist dentists

# Interior Designer | Al Architecture and Design

Jan 2015 - July 2015 | Bangkok, Thailand

- Created home, apartment and office plans using AutoCAD 3D Max, Sketch Up, and Photoshop
- Completed site visits and selected colors and materials to match design concept

# **EDUCATION**

## Flatiron School

Jan 2020 - May 2020 | Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Immersive Program

### **Bangkok University**

Feb 2011 - Apr 2014 | Bangkok, Thailand